B I J A Y A G A U T A M

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

4 years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing various range of application in an agile environment with the help of technology and tools such as Adobe products for design, MS visual studio for development, and SQL Server for database integration.



647-278-4001 www.bjagautam.com bijayagautam.ca@outlook.com Brampton, ON L7A 1Y8

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

Certificate of Achievement

Graphic Design for Print and Web : Current Humber College, Etobicoke, ON, Canada

Web Design and Development : Apr 2020 Humber College, Etobicoke, ON, Canada

Bachelors of Science

Computer Information System : May 2015Tarleton State University, Stephenville, TX, USA

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Creative Cloud:

InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, XD, After Effects

Languages:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node JS, C#, SQL, XAML

Technologies:

MVC 4.0, ASP.Net 4.5/4.0/3.5/3.0

Database:

Oracle SQL Developer/SQL Server

Development Tools:

Microsoft VS Code, Visual Studio 2012/2015

Service Oriented Architecture:

Windows Communication Foundation(WCF), .NET Web Services, SOAP

DESIGN FOCUS & INTERESTS





Responsive

Accessible

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wells Fargo: Des Moines, IA, USA

Application Systems Engineer: Sep 2018 – Jul 2019
Used MVC application design architecture to design and develop responsive modern web application, migrated existing application which was built in PHP to C#.

Collaborated with DevOps engineers to secure sensitive application token and for deployment/release process.

Accenture: Austin, TX, USA

Application Developer: Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

Collaborated with business analyst in identifying existing application defects from development backlog and provided proper solution in a timely manner. Unit tested application functionalities, security, and navigation system as well as browser capability.

Dell Inc. Round Rock, TX, USA

Software Developer: Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

Design and developed custom encryption and decryption windows application with advance algorithm to encrypt sensitive information, developed validation rules for credit application bureau search. Provided solution for fortify detected system issues and deployed application to higher environments.

CyberSolve IT Inc. Carrollton, TX, USA

.NET Developer: Jul 2015 - Sep 2016

Learned new technologies through various training, used team foundation server to maintain code and version control as well as enhanced existing application by analyzing business objectives. Involved in translating business requirements into technical data.